

Aman Yadav

UG Student, B.Tech CSE (2023)

PROFILE

Address Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh 201001

Phone Number +91-9717617021

Website

https://yadav-aman.github.io

Email Address

amansy04@gmail.com

Date Of Birth 26 December 1999

Linkedin

aman-yadav07

Github

yadav-aman

AWARDS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

SNU-HCL

July Hackathon Winner 2020 **HCL**

Deans List November Shiv Nadar 2020 University

IICDC Govt. of India

March 2019

Ideonator AIC-SNU

November 2019

Toycathon

June **Finalist** 2021 Govt. Of India

CERTIFICATIONS

Google IT

Automation with September 2020 Python

Coursera

A 6 course specialization offered by Google on coursera

Deep Learning **Specialization** Coursera

September 2020

A 5 course Specialization offered by coursera.

LANGUAGES

English Fluent

Hindi

Native Tongue

Punjabi

Familiar

HOBBIES

Badminton

Travelling

Art

Coding

Digital Art and Illustrations

ABOUT ME

A self motivated student, developer and a lifelong learner with an open and inquisitive mind. I love to code, and I'm inclined towards open-source technology and cybersecurity. I am always open for new challenges and opportunities. I am a team player and always willing to step up as a leader. Some of my key strengths are:

- Hands on programming experience in Java and Python
- Commitment and determination to execute a task to completion
- Familiarity with *nix Operating systems
- Aptitude for automation, information security and software development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Surge-SNU

(December 2020 - Present)

Graphic Designer

The Annual Sports Fest of Shiv Nadar University

Go Green - SNU

Marketing and Design Team

(November 2020 - September 2021)

A social and environmental club which aims at a cleaner and greener society.

Blue Circle - SNU

(September 2020 - August 2021)

Volunteer

Peer support guide to help freshmen getting accustomed with the university

HackData

Volunteer

Annual Inter University tech fest of SNU

EDUCATION

(July 2019 - Present) Shiv Nadar University

Bachelors Computer Science & Engineering

8.88 CGPA

10 CGPA

10+2 Schooling

New Era School

SKILLS

Python Java

Linux Git

C/C++ **JavaScript** React HTML/CSS

DBMS Open CV

PROJECTS

CodeForces Helper

https://github.com/yadav-aman/codeforces-helper

CLI python app to automatically extract and organize the sample test-cases of a given code-forces contest in separate directory, with cross-platform support and automatic testing of code against all the test cases.

Gesture Control Mouse

https://github.com/yadav-aman/HandTracking

Machine Learning based virtual mouse made using Open-CV to control mouse using hand tracking

Flask Based Ecommerce Site

https://github.com/yadav-aman/HCL-HackathonQ2

A fully functional flask based Ecommerce site with recommendation system.

2-3 Tree Visualizer

https://github.com/yadav-aman/TwoThreeTree

A visual representation of 2-3 Tree using JavaFX.

Voting System

(May 2020 - September https://github.com/yadav-aman/CSD-2020)

project

Handling to handle various operations.

A voting system written in C, which uses data structures like AVL trees and Linked List along with String processing, File

TODO CLI

A python CLI TODO app to organize tasks at hand.